<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="david-recio.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="david-recio.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-21T15:32:46-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">David Recio’s Blog</title><entry><title type="html">Comparing the Sentiment of Reviews and Ratings, with VADER and BERT</title><link href="david-recio.com/2022/10/21/vader-bert-podcast-reviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparing the Sentiment of Reviews and Ratings, with VADER and BERT" /><published>2022-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/2022/10/21/vader-bert-podcast-reviews</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In another notebook we trained a recommender using on a million ratings from Apple Podcasts. However, we didn't use the content of the reviews, which are an additional source of signal of user preference. Some of that signal can be extracted using sentiment analysis. In this post we will do so using two methods: VADER and BERT.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Training distilBERT to Predict Podcast Ratings</title><link href="david-recio.com/2022/10/21/bert-fine-tune-podcast-reviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training distilBERT to Predict Podcast Ratings" /><published>2022-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/2022/10/21/bert-fine-tune-podcast-reviews</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we will use the Hugging Face API and PyTorch to fine-tune distilBERT on podcast reviews. We will train it to predict the rating from the title and body of the review. By converting ratings to sentiment, this also gives us a sentiment classifier. We will use Ray Tune for hyperparameter search and we will also evaluate the model in various ways.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Titanic has a Leak</title><link href="david-recio.com/2022/04/11/titanic-leak.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Titanic has a Leak" /><published>2022-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/2022/04/11/titanic-leak</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We will explore a source of data leakage in the popular Titanic competition on Kaggle: Passengers traveling together have similar survival outcomes and this correlation can be used to make predictions for the test set in a way that wouldn't be possible in reality. To prevent the leakage we implement a leak-proof cross-validation. We compare the accuracy of an XGBoost classifier to various baselines to investigate which role, if any, the leakage is playing in the predictions of our classifier.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Latent Space of Podcasts</title><link href="david-recio.com/2022/03/19/podcasts-recommender.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Latent Space of Podcasts" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/2022/03/19/podcasts-recommender</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We train a podcast recommender using matrix-based collaborative filtering. Visualizing the resulting latent factors gives us some insight into what the model has learned.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is the effect of flipped classroom groups on grades?</title><link href="david-recio.com/2022/03/19/grades-analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the effect of flipped classroom groups on grades?" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>david-recio.com/2022/03/19/grades-analysis</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We explore the possible effects of student groups on final grades. For this we implement hypothesis tests from three different paradigms: the permutation test, a semi-parametric bootstrap test, and ANOVA. As part of the analysis we compare the different tests through simulation.]]></summary></entry></feed>